《黑镜》
《白熊》
有人吗
Hello?
(十月)
喂
Hello?
你们好
能帮帮我吗
Can you help me?
你们知道我是谁吗  我...
Do you know who I am? I... I...
我不记得我是谁了
I can't remember who I am.
喂
Hello?
你们知道我是谁吗
Do you know who I am?
求你们了
Please!
我想不起来了
I can't remember.
小姐  帮帮我
Lady, help me!
帮帮我
Help me!
请帮帮我
Help me, please.
救命
Oh! Help!
救救我  他有枪  救救我
Help me. He's got a gun! Help me!
快  得走了
Hey! We have to go!
快啊
Come on!
上帝啊  救命
Oh, my god! Help!
上帝
Oh, my god!
快回去
Stay back!
快  退回去
Back! Get back!
退回去  快
Get back. Back!
让我进去  让我进去
Let me in. Let me in!
救救我  救救我
Help me! Help me!
见鬼
Shit!
那儿有门
There's a door round there.
上锁了
It's locked.
未必啊
You don't know that!
要密码
There's a keypad.
我们得试试
We should try it.
快趴下  谁站起来  就会脑袋开花的
Get down! Anybody stands up, they'll shoot their heads off.
他想杀我  怎么回事啊
He's trying to kill me! What's going on?
闭嘴  我在想办法
Shut up! I'm trying to think!
他看见你了  快躲起来
He can see you. Get back.
我的天啊  这些人都是怎么了
Oh, my god! What's wrong with those people?!
他们为什么不帮我们  就站那儿看呢
Why aren't they helping us? They're just watching...
你他妈去哪了
Where the fuck have you been?
什么
What?
去拿那个灭火器
Get that extinguisher.
我不能  我做不到
I can't! I can't do it!
去拿  快去
Get it. Get it now!
好  好  好
Ok... ok... ok... ok... ok...
快
Come on.
快  从地上滑过来
Quickly. Slide it to me.
戴米恩  他要是进来了你就抓住他  还有枪
Damien, if he climbs through, you grab him and you grab his gun.
我不行
I can't...
你能行
You can.
他会开枪的
He will shoot me.
没别的办法
You have to!
我去把门砸开
I'm going to smash the lock off that door,
你帮他对付枪手
you help him with gun guy.
他没法冲我们所有人开枪
He can't shoot all of us.
开火之后还得装弹
If he fires, he has to reload.
我们要么扑倒他要么直接跑  明白吗
We either rush him or run, OK?
我不行
I can't do this!
没别的办法
We have no choice!
帮他一把
Help him.
戴米恩
Damien!
天啊
Oh, my...
抓住他
Get him!
趴下
Get down.
嘘
Shh!
靠
Fuck!
不
No.
嘘
Shh!
得走了  快
We have to go, come on.
擦
Shit.
蹲着
Stay down.
他们是谁  怎么打扮成这样
Who are they? Why do they look like that?
他们喜欢吓唬人
They like scaring people.
什么
What?
好了
OK.
我们得跑去那个缺口
We have to run for that opening.
不行  他们会看到我们的
No, they'll see us.
他们要是忙着对付他  我们就能脱身了
If they're busy with him we can lose the hunters, OK?
不
No.
- 跟住我  好吗  - 好
- You just stay with me. OK?  -  OK.
准备好了吗  快来
Ready... Come on...
等下
Wait.
Wait!
看客有时候会在窗前等着  保持观望
The onlookers sometimes wait in the windows, keeping lookout.
他们肯定就是这么发现我们的
I'm pretty sure that's how they find us.
用摄像机
Through the cameras somehow.
看客一发现你
Onlookers spot you
几分钟内恐怖混蛋就会赶来
and a few minutes later the scary bastards turn up.
太疯狂了  简直太疯狂了
This is mad, this is just mad.
你得撑着
Look, you have to hold it together
照我说的做  要不就没命了
and do what I say or you'll get us killed.
我
I...
我在一栋房子里醒来  都不知道是不是我家
I woke up in this house and I don't even know if it's my house.
连自己是谁都不知道
I don't even know who I am.
你肯定知道点什么吧
You must know something.
我觉得这是我女儿
I think this is my daughter.
但是你不确定
But you don't know?
都不知道她在哪
She could be anywhere.
可能你是想自杀来着  能说得通吗
Maybe you tried to kill yourself. Would that explain it?
确实有些药片
There was pills.
我不怪你
I don't blame you.
那个开始后  不少人走了那条路
Lots have tried that fun fork in the road since it started.
什么开始后
Since what started?
你真不知道
You really don't know?
不知道
No.
有个信号  内容是闪动的图片
There was a signal... Like pictures, flashing pictures.
它们出现在每台电视  每台电脑
They just appeared on every TV, every computer,
任何有屏幕的东西上
anything with a screen.
我看到过  我看到过
I saw it. I saw it.
蹲下
Get down.
信号对人们产生了影响
They did something to people.
几乎每个人都变成了看客
Like, almost everybody just became onlookers,
开始旁观  录像
started watching, filming stuff,
就像漠不关心的旁观者一样
like spectators who don't give a shit about what happens.
现在十之八九都是这样的人了
That's, like, nine out of ten people now.
但我们没有
But not us.
有些人没有受到影响  我也不知道为什么
Some of us weren't affected. I don't know why.
比如那个拿着枪的人  还有那个女人
Like that man with the gun and that woman.
我叫他们"猎手"
I call them "hunters".
也许你已经注意到了  他们就是干这个的
You might've noticed that's what they do.
他们自己没事  但随即意识到
They seemed normal to begin with, but they realised
自己可以随心所欲
they could do what they wanted
就开始到处抢掠  偷车  因为没人管
and they started taking stuff, nicking cars cos they could,
他们为所欲为  不仅对物  还对人
doing what they like and not just with things, with people.
情况愈发糟糕  现在他们还有观众了
It got worse and worse. And now they've got an audience.
这个...电视上的这个东西...
So this... this thing on the TV, the...
信号
The signal.
就是他们这样做的原因吗
That, that's what's doing it. That's what's making them act like this?
我猜他们其实一直都是这样的人
I guess they were always like that underneath.
只不过现在规则变了  没有人管了
Just needed the rules to change, for no-one to intervene.
我们要怎么办  怎么做
What we going to do? What we going to do?
什么都不做  我们逃
Do? Do nothing. We get out.
逃去哪
Where's "out"?
我们在这里  得向南去这里
We're here. We need to head south of here.
那儿的发射机已被毁  那里很安全
They've knocked the transmitters out, it's OK there.
电视信号发射机  传送那个信号
The TV transmitters, they carry it.
在我们和安全区之间只有一台发射机
There's only one between us and the safe zone and
我们要去毁掉它  就在这里
we're going to knock it out. See, it's here.
白熊
White Bear.
怎么了
What?
白熊
White Bear...
和两个最好的朋友一起野餐
A picnic with my two best friends.
天哪  你怎么回事
Jesus, what is it with you?
白熊  你说了白熊
White Bear, you said White Bear...
那又如何
So?!
不管你有什么问题
Look, whatever's wrong with you,
现在都得振作起来  行吗
you have to keep it together. OK?
听我说  别出去
Listen to me! Don't go out there.
你们怎么回事
What's your problem?
想看热闹吗
Huh? You want something to look at?
那我就让你们看
Cos I'll give you something to look at!
我们得走了
We have to get out there.
不  我要跟他们谈谈
No, I want to talk to him.
我想跟你们谈谈
I want to talk to you!
这下不好玩了  是吗
It's not so funny now, is it?
快放下
Put it down.
我只是想知道他们在看什么
I just want to see what they're looking at.
我说了  快放下
I said put it down.
这东西很危险
It's dangerous.
他们的电话很危险
Their phones, they're dangerous.
是那个信号
It's the signal.
屏幕上有那个图案
The images are on them, they're on the screen.
什么
What?
别看它
Don't look at it!
Don't look at it.
杰迈玛
Jemima...
不  这不对劲  不对劲
No, no. This is all wrong. This is all wrong!
他们追来了  快跑  跑啊
They're coming. Run! Run!
上车
Get in.
上车  快点
Get in. Come on.
快来啊
Come on.
快啊  他们追上来了  快来啊
Come on, now! They're coming! Quick.
抓紧点  快上车
Come on, hurry up. Get in.
你刚才差点撞死我们
You nearly killed us back there.
我又不知道你们会突然冲出来
Yeah, well, I wasn't expecting you to be there, was I?
我救了你们的命
I just saved your lives.
你们就不能说声谢谢
You are not like a wee thank you' would be nice.
真该从你们身上碾过去
I should've just run yous over.
你是谁
Who are you?
你又是谁
这问题不难  对吗
It's not a hard question, is it?
我认得你
I know... I know you.
是吗  你要是认得我  我们在哪见过
Do you? Well, where did we meet, if you know me?
我猜也是
No. Didn't think so, yeah.
她现在很混乱  状态不好
She's confused. She's not in a good way.
看出来了
Yeah, I'll say.
你们在这儿干什么
So what are yous doing out here anyway?
朝南走
Heading south.
那可不明智  南边全封死了
That's not a good move. It's all blocked up down there.
那里有台发射机
There's a transmitter there...
你没听懂
I don't think you understand.
我说"那可不明智"
When I said, "It's not a good move",
意思是我不会开车送你们过去
that means I'm not driving you down there.
我知道个安全的地方
I know a safe place we can go.
那片树林
The woods.
你说的地方是树林
Your safe place is in the woods.
你怎么知道
How'd you know that?
我不知道
I don't... I don't know.
天啊  也许你是认识我
Christ, maybe you do know me.
我们停车  然后下车
Yeah, we pull up and we get out.
我们讲了话  那里没人追我们
We talk. There's no-one chasing us.
神秘梅格附身(英国占星家)
Mystic Meg.
然后会发生什么
And then what happens?
我们会吃东西
We eat.
说了吧  这儿没信号
Told you. No bars.
他们不会找到这儿来的
They'll never find us here.
这是你女儿吗
That your daughter?
我想应该是
Yeah, I think so.
她人呢
Where is she?
我不知道
I don't know.
你手腕怎么回事
What'd you do to your wrists?
不知道
Don't know.
你有精神病史吗
History of mental illness?
我打赌你肯定有
Yeah, I bet you do. Lay money on it.
那你呢
What about you?
我怎么了
What about me?
得过精神病吗  有什么弱点
Mental illness, weaknesses...
人无完人
Everyone's got weaknesses.
你俩的弱点肯定不少
Yeah, you two have got more than most, I'd say.
所以你们才会成为目标  脆弱
That's why you're on the receiving end, you see. Vulnerable.
谁的目标
Receiving end of what?
这一切  都是因为你们太好欺负
This. Everything that's going on. Easy pickings.
那你的弱点是什么
What's your weaknesses then?
我的弱点吗
My weaknesses?
我可以给你看看  想看吗
Show you if you want. You want to see it?
待在这儿别动  你们会喜欢这个的
Wait there don't move. You're going to like this.
也许不太喜欢
Not a lot.
最好不是裸体主义
This better not be naturism.
你做梦去吧
Yeah, in your dreams.
你跑我就开枪
Run and I'll shoot you in the back.
好了  过来
Right, come over here.
站过去
Stand there.
你  来  把这个戴上
You, here, put this on.
戴上  反着戴  遮住眼睛
Put it on. Backwards, so it covers your eyes.
手搭在她肩上  搭好了
Put your hands on her shoulders. Keep them there.
你现在是她的眼睛  懂吗
You're her eyes now, all right?
你背后是杆猎枪
And that is a shotgun, OK?
一旦开枪  你们俩都会被劈成两半
If I pull this trigger, it's going to cut you, both in half.
所以别捣鬼
So no funny business, all right?
好了  走吧
Right, off you go.
往前走  穿过树丛
Straight ahead. Keep going through the trees.
快点  走快点
Come on, pick up the pace.
下面给你们准备了一个不错的操场
Got a lovely playground for you down there.
没错  穿过去
That's it, through here.
没错  继续往前
That's it, straight ahead.
抓住她
Grab her!
好了  帮她把帽子拿掉
Right, now take her balaclava off.
下去
Get down there.
见鬼
Oh, fuck.
快点
Come on.
走到那个梯子旁边
Head towards that ladder.
过去
Get down there.
好  停下
Right, stop.
都给我跪下
Get on your knees, both of you.
包给我
Give me that bag.
该死的包
Fucking bag.
你  趴下
You, get down.
别哭了
Stop whingeing.
你他妈别哭了
Stop fucking crying.
别哭了
Stop it.
喂
Yeah.
我在树林这边  对  别急
I'm down in that wood spot. Yeah, yeah, yeah. Easy.
我就把她们绑在树上什么的
I'll just lash them to a tree or something like that, you know.
你快点过来  我要开始了
Just hurry up and get down here. I want to get started.
等会儿...
It's going to piss...
妈的
Fuck!
你同伴跑了
Your mate's fucked off.
你麻烦更大了  小妞
You're in double trouble now, missus.
趴到木头上去  动作快点
Get up on that log. Now! Move!
把手放进去  把手放进去
Get your hands through there. Get your hands through there!
放进去
Right through.
把胳膊抬起来  抬起来
Push your arms up. Push them!
把胳膊抬高
Get them up there!
我们今天要上演一出好戏了
Are we going to put a show on for these guys today, eh?
看看老子包里都有什么
Let's see what Daddy's got in the bag, shall we? Oh...
天啊
Oh! Oh, mama.
救命啊  救命啊
Help me! Help me!
求求你们  救救我
Please, just help me!
你们为什么不帮我
Why aren't you doing anything?
救救我啊
You guys, help me, please.
救命啊  求求你们
Help me, please.
我是个人啊
I'm a human being!
他们不会救你的  只会围观
They're not going to help you. They're going to watch.
乖乖  我现在要做的
What I'm going to do here darling,
就是用这个直接刺穿你的...
is just going to push this straight through your...
救命
Help me!
谢谢  谢谢  太感谢了
Thank you. Thank you. Thank you!
谢我什么
For what?
谢谢你回来救我
For coming back for me.
我是回来拿包的
I came back for this.
这一路上还会遇到更多这种人
There's more like him on the way.
快走
Come on.
白熊离这儿不远
Whitebear's not far from here.
我们加把劲
If we step on it
也许能在他们追上来之前把它关掉
we might be able to shut it down before they get us.
如果关不掉怎么办
What happens if we can't shut it down?
一定能关掉的
Well, we can.
怎么关  要黑了系统还是什么
How? Do we hack into it, or something?
不用侵入系统  烧掉控制室就行了
We don't hack anything. We burn the control room down.
一点不难  只要在四周浇上汽油
It's not hard, we just slosh a load of petrol round,
点上火  切断电源什么的就行了
strike a light and fucks the electrics or something.
拿着
Here.
我包里
In the bag.
是发射场的平面图
It's the plans for the transmitter compound.
我计划很长时间了
I've been planning this, you know.
杰迈玛
Jemima?
乖乖躺下  亲爱的  来
Lie down for me, darling. Go on.
是个游戏
It's a game.
对  就像泰迪熊那样
Yeah, just like what Teddy does.
乖乖躺下  亲爱的
Lie down for me, darling.
掉头
Turn around!
什么
What?
白熊  白熊有些不对劲
White Bear, there's something not right about White Bear.
我记得
I remember that!
你也"记得"树林
You "Remembered" the woods, too.
抱歉我不能相信你的预感
Sorry if I don't trust your hunches.
看上去安全
OK. Looks clear.
好了
OK.
他总算还有点用
He was good for something, after all.
快  我们该走了
Hurry up, we need to go!
快点  出来
Come on... Get out...
跟我来
Come with me...
(白熊发射塔)
和两个最好的朋友一起野餐
A picnic with my two best friends.
(白熊发射塔)
来
Come on.
这边
This way.
该死  他们随时会来  把平面图给我
Oh, shit. They'll be here any minute. Give me the plan.
发射塔在那里
The transmitter tower's over there
电缆一直铺到那栋建筑里
and the cabling runs underground into that building.
走吧
Come on!
不出所料
Thought so.
我们走
Let's go!
退后
Get back.
否则我烧了一切  我说真的  退后
Or everything goes up. I mean it... Stay back.
别过来
Stay back.
谢谢大家
Thank you.
我猜你很好奇为什么在这儿
So. I guess you're wondering why you're here?
该告诉你你是谁了
Well, it's time to tell you who you are.
你那时比较精神
You've looked better.
你认出他了吗
Do you recognise him?
嗯
Uh...Yeah.
你的未婚夫  伊安·兰诺克
Your fiance, Iain Rannoch.
确切点说  是已故的未婚夫
Or, should I say, was your fiance.
如果你还没猜到  你们俩不太受欢迎
In case you haven't guessed, the pair of you aren't very popular.
但我倒是可以说
But I'll tell you what you are though.
你们很有名
You're famous.
维多利亚·斯基兰的审判今日终于结束
The trial of Victoria Skillane finally concluded today,
她被判有罪
the verdict, guilty.
由于其未婚夫伊安·兰诺克
Together with her fiance Iain Rannoch,
在拘留期间死去  审判一度延迟
whose death in custody had delayed the trial,
两人在离家不远处
Skillane abducted six-year-old
绑架了六岁的杰迈玛·赛克斯
Jemima Sykes just miles from her home,
从而引发全国范围的搜寻
prompting a nationwide search
她父母也深切哀恳绑匪放人
amidst emotional pleas from her parents.
几个月来  孩子的失踪始终谜团重重
For months, the youngster's disappearance had been a mystery,
唯一的线索是她特别的白色泰迪熊
the sole clue being her distinctive white teddy bear,
在离家两英里处的路边被人发现
discovered in a lay-by two miles from the family home.
白熊变成了杰迈玛搜寻行动的永久标志
The white bear became an enduring symbol in the hunt for Jemima,
搜寻最终在当地的树林结束
a hunt that ended in a local forest.
杰迈玛的尸体就在这里被发现
Jemima's body was found here.
她被人裹在一个睡袋里烧死
It had been wrapped in a sleeping bag and burnt.
在斯基兰手机里
The couple were caught
发现了一段令人发指的
after harrowing footage of Jemima's torture
折磨并杀害杰迈玛的录像
and murder was discovered on a mobile phone
随后这对情侣被捕
in Skillane's possession.
纹有特别纹身的伊安·兰诺克
Iain Rannoch, identified by his distinctive tattoo,
杀害了幼女  而维多利亚·斯基兰则在旁拍摄
killed the youngster as Victoria Skillane held the camera.
斯基兰泣不成声
Breaking down in tears,
承认拍下了杰迈玛的临终时刻
Skillane admitted to filming Jemima's final moments,
并声称她是受未婚夫逼迫而协助他
claiming her fiance had pressured her into helping him,
坚称她是受了他的蛊惑
maintaining she was "under his spell".
而陪审团则不相信斯基兰的说法
The jury was not convinced by Skillane's story,
法官也不信
and neither was the judge,
并认为她"十分恶劣"  心地歹毒
who labelled her a "Uniquely wicked" and poisonous individual.
他说"你狂热地围观了杰迈玛受虐的过程
"You were an enthusiastic spectator to Jemima's suffering.
甚至着迷于她的痛苦"
"You actively revelled in her anguish", he said,
理应适当增刑
adding her punishment would be proportionate and considered.
伊安·兰诺克在囚室里上吊
By hanging himself in his cell,
很多人认为他逃过了制裁
many believe Iain Rannoch evaded justice.
于是公众将目光转向他的同谋者
The public mood is now focussed on ensuring his accomplice
确保她不能这样逃脱
Can't do the same.
帕特里克·雷希  UKN
Patrick Lacey, UKN.
求你们
Please!
别哭了  鳄鱼的眼泪真让人恶心
Oh, don't start crying. Crocodile tears are making me sick!
杀人犯
Murderer!
你看着他行凶的时候可没哭
There were no tears when you watched him do what he did.
你拍下了他对那小姑娘的恶行
You filmed what he did. A poor wee girl.
她那么无助  那么害怕  而你只是看着
Helpless and terrified and you just watched.
你现在什么感觉
How do you like it now?
说啊
How do you like it?!
杀人犯
Murderer!
带她下去
Get her out of here.
把她扔回去
Throw her back to where she came from.
不不  不要这样
No! No! Please...
不  求你们了
NO! Please!
晚上好  市民们
Good evening, citizens!
谢谢各位今晚的到来
Thank you so much for coming tonight. OK!
我们达到了今天的高潮
We're at the climax of our day.
想拍多少照片就拍吧
Take as many photographs as you want,
尽可能多拍一些
take as many photographs as you can,
但最重要的是  我需要你们做的是
but most importantly, what I need from you
大声高喊
is to shout and scream
让那贱人知道你们在这儿
and let that bitch know that youse are out here.
让表演开始吧
Let's get this show on the road!
杀人的贱人
Murdering bitch!
恶毒的巫婆
Evil witch!
臭婊子
Dirty whore!
烧死那贱人
Burn the bitch!
杀人犯
Murderer!
下地狱吧
Burn in hell!
杀了我吧  求你杀了我吧
Kill me. Please just kill me.
求你了
Please...
你总是这么说
That's what you always say.
今天挺够呛的  但这个会让你都忘记
You've had a bad day, but this will wipe it clean.
让你有心情再来一遍
Get you in the mood to start again.
不  求你  放开我
No! Please! Get off me!
你要干什么
What are you doing?
大约三十分钟
Takes about 30 minutes...
就能好了
..For it to fully do the business.
在此期间
So while it does....
我们看会儿娱乐节目吧
Why don't we watch some in-flight entertainment?
不要
Please, no.
- 健康食品  比如苹果  - 停下吧
- Healthy stuff, like apples. -  Please stop.
你肯定喜欢
You should enjoy this.
可是你拍的呢
You shot it.
把它们放一起  这样我的两个朋友
Made it together, so that my two friends...
和两个最好的朋友一起野餐
Erm... A picnic for me and my two best friends.
救救我
Help me.
(欢迎来到白熊正义公园)
好了  各位  我们即将进入公园
OK everyone, we're about to head into the park
接下来就交给巴克斯特了
so I'll hand you over to Baxter.
(白熊正义公园  访客中心)
(白熊正义公园)
谢谢
Thank you.
我们的角色都十分重要  你们也是
All of our roles are very, very important, yours included.
你们要遵守一些基本的规则
Now, yours come with some basic rules.
第一条  不许说话
Rule number one, no talking,
不止对她  跟其他人也不行  除非是要紧事
not just to her, but each other as well, unless it's essential.
我们希望让她相信你们都被催眠了
We're trying to get her to believe that youse are all mesmerised.
我知道  但到目前  她都信了
I know, I know, I know, but she's believed it up to now.
(白熊正义公园)
(停车场和服务区)
第二条规则  保持距离
OK, rule number two, keep your distance.
这一条万分的重要
I can't stress the importance of this one enough, OK?
别忘了  她是个危险的人
Don't forget, she's a dangerous individual.
把她想成一个在逃的狮子
Imagine that she's an escaped lion.
昨天她向人群投掷了东西
Now yesterday, she threw a projectile,
如果她离得太近我们都会插手
and we will step in if she gets too close.
我们都有电击枪
We're all equipped with tasers,
但那样就会中断进程  这一天也白费了
but then we're into story shutdown and we've all wasted a day.
所以各位最好保持三米以上的距离
So it's best to keep your distance at least three metres back.
你们可以用摄像机聚焦
You can use your camera zoom.
最后  但也同样重要  是好好玩
Last, but not least, enjoy yourself.
这可能是最重要的一条了
That's probably the most important rule of all, OK?
拍照片  在林子里跑
Take photographs, run around through the woods,
但要小心
but try and stay safe.
我们会随时监控保证你们的安全
We'll be keeping an eye on you, making sure you're all OK.
大家进园好好玩吧
So get out there, enjoy yourselves
我们来献上一出好戏吧  来吧
and let's make this show happen, people! Come on!
(白熊正义公园  直播)
瞧啊  她在那儿
Look, there she is.
不知道  我挺累的
Don't know yet. I'm kind of knackered.
我也是
Me, too.
她离开家了  最多两分钟
She's just leaving her house now. Two minutes tops.
好的
Right, you are.
该我们了
We're on.
小心
Watch out!
他想杀我  怎么回事啊
He's trying to fucking kill me. What's going on?
去拿那个灭火器
Get that extinguisher.
没事  他们走了
It's OK, they've gone.
真像回事啊
Convincing, eh?
还有两分钟
We got two minutes.
救命
Help!
救救我
Help me!
真令人激动
Early screamer.
今晚真令人激动
It's an early screamer tonight.
大家闹起来  开始吧
So keep the noise up and let's go!